Today I fucked up by changing gas suppliers which resulted in me paying for electricity for the—first
time in 11 years. This story starts in 2013. I bought a new house in Pennsylvania and signed
up for utilities with a local company that combines. Both electric and gas in one bill.
I set up auto pace I automatically pay bills without even looking at them. As the years go by,
I never look at the actual bill. Only once in a while I'm bewildered how cheap my gas and
electricity bill is. Averaging about $65 per month. Maybe two months ago I was talking to my
sister who lives nearby about it and she couldn't believe. It either, needless to say I didn't dig
deeper and went on my merry way. Maybe a few days afterwards I was shopping in Walmart and there
was a representative of a competing. Gas company offering a $15 Walmart gift card for switching my gas
supplier. I told him that I don't use much gas anyway so the savings would be minimal but
extra $15 to. Spend at Walmart never heard anyone. Famous last words. He even tells me that I have
three days to change my mind before they actually switch me and then I have another three months to cancel
if I'm not happy. I got my $15 gift right after I finished the sign-up process. Today I get an email
from my gas and electric company with a much higher total than normal. For the first time I actually
look at my bill and compare it to my previous bills and that's when I see it. Before the switch
to a new gas supplier I never paid for any electricity. I guess the change in my gas supplier made them
rejig the entire account and they finally started. Counting my electricity usage. My bill is now
$100 higher than before. For 11 years I was blissfully unaware that I had free electricity.
I immediately called the new gas supplier and canceled their service but I'm sure that the
Kraken is out and I'll have to pay for electricity from now on. Because I never paid for electricity
I don't even know much much this fuck up is going to cost me in the long run. Fortunately I'm moving
in a year so the damage will be limited. But still, TL, DR, I exchanged a $15 Walmart gift card to pay extra
$1000 plus per year.